Cindy Burton

Freelance Artist And Full Stack Webdev In Training

Contact

Address

Denver, CO, 80218

Phone

(720) 975-4658

E-mail

cindy.brton@gmail.com

WWW

cndbrtn.github.io/portfolio

Skills

2D design

Excellent

HTML5

Excellent

Business Management

Excellent

Creating visual art

Excellent

web design

Excellent

Web user interfaces

Very Good

JavaScript

Creative problem solver with over 6 years experience managing a personal art business, 20 years experience with HTML and CSS and a recently acquired proficiency in front end Javascript and interactive user interfaces.

Expertise includes traditional media (ex: oil paints) and digital media (ex: photoshop and clip studio), setting goals and schedules for self directed work, communicating with clients to ensure they get exactly what they dreamed of, a strong sense of design and aesthetic, color theory, marketing via social media, and 2D design.

Soon to be graduate of DU full stack webdev boot camp seeking opportunity in web development. Highly poised and dedicated with strong education and training in design principles and programming languages.

Work History

2014-05 -Current

Freelance Artist

Self-Employed, Denver, CO

- Anticipated design issues and proved to be proactive in developing effective solutions
- Consulted with clients to discuss preferences, styles and ideas for commissions
- Maintained and shared portfolios of artistic work to demonstrate styles, interests, and abilities with potential customers
- Made use of materials, such as ink, watercolors, charcoal, oil, computer software, paints, and pencils, to complete unique piece for customers
- Managed technological considerations to meet defined goals
- Designed graphics for websites, logos and promotions for marketing purposes
- Learned new software packages in addition to traditional art methods
- Developed marketing and sales strategies to maximize business success
- Ordered and maintained adequate supply of materials, supplies and equipment
- Researched drawings of characters and environmental elements for inspiration
- Established and maintained productive, professional

Very Good JQuery Web Development Software Clip Studio Paint Excellent **VSCode**

working relationships

- Resolved client concerns quickly and professionally
- Developed art and design concepts
- Managed day-to-day business operations and made strategic decisions
- Developed artistic visual products while working within defined technical constraints
- Planned, organized and scheduled work
- Contributed to creative process through original ideas and inspiration
- Handled dozens emails/DMs/messages per day from clients and customers

2019-10 -Current

Webdev student

DU full stack webdev boot camp, Denver, CO, CO Working quickly towards full stack proficiency web development by building a strong understanding of fundamentals, design, troubleshooting, and user interactivity.

Education

2019-10 - Current	Certificate of Completion: Full Stack Webdev
	Full Stack Webdev Boot Camp For Women - University of Denver, CO
2011-09 - 2014-05	Masters of Fine Arts: Video And Performance Art, Sculpture School of The Museum of Fine Arts - Boston, MA
2005-08 - 2009-05	Bachelors of Fine Arts: Painting Ringling College of Art And Design - Sarasota, FL

Accomplishments

- Owning my own business for 6 years
- Constantly learning new methods, materials, and skills

Photoshop

Excellent

Languages

Native

Japanese

Novice

Certifications

2020-04 Full stack webdev

Hobbies

Hobbies include:

- Learning new things every day
- Keeping over 50 indoor plants alive
- Puppy training through positive reinforcement
- Creating art and craft projects for pleasure and personal enrichment